northwestpharmacy.com 2015-09-06

# Privacy Policy

## Introduction

At NorthWestPharmacy.com Inc., your health and the protection of your personal information is our top priority. We make considerable efforts to safeguard your confidentiality and protect your personal information. 

This privacy policy covers the privacy practices of [www.NorthWestPharmacy.com](https://www.northwestpharmacy.com/) owned and operated by NorthWestPharmacy.com Inc. ("NorthWestPharmacy.com"). This privacy policy describes how NorthWestPharmacy.com Inc. collects and uses the personal information you provided on our web site: www.NorthWestPharmacy.com. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. 

Updated: January 07, 2015

NorthWestPharmacy.com has received TRUSTe's Privacy Seal signifying that this privacy statement and our practices have been reviewed for compliance with the TRUSTe program viewable on the validation page available by clicking the TRUSTe seal. The TRUSTe program covers only information that is collected through this web site, www.NorthWestPharmacy.com. 

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact TRUSTe [here](https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request). 

## The Types of Personal Information We Collect

To order from this website, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on the registration form. During registration and account creation, you are required to provide your contact information (such as name, address, phone number and email address) and you are also required to create a password. We use this information to contact you about the services on our site in which you have expressed interest. 

Once you have created an account, you are then able to order prescription drugs as well as over the counter drugs. For orders for over the counter drugs, we request no additional information other than that which has been provided during the registration and account creation process as mentioned above. To order prescription medications, we will require additional medical information about the patient (which may be you or a family member) for whom the prescription has been ordered. This information includes: name, height, weight, date of birth, gender, the existence and types of drug allergies, medications requested, medical history information, details of your existing medications, prescription information, and the name of your primary physician and his or her contact information. 

The choice to provide us with personal information is always yours. However, your decision to withhold particular details may limit the products and services we are able to provide and makes it more difficult for us to advise you or suggest appropriate alternatives. If we are unable to accommodate your request based on the information that has been provided, we may ask for additional details in order to serve you best. We may also maintain a file containing contact history that is used for customer inquiry purposes. We may collect anonymous/non-personal information. Anonymous/non-personal information is information that cannot be associated with or traced back to a specific individual or business entity. 

## The Purposes for Which We Use Personal Information

We use your or your family members' personal information to communicate with you, send you newsletters, enhance your visit to our site, process orders, and effectively provide the products and services you have requested. We may provide your or your family members personal information to a licensed physician to review and approve your prescription. We may use personal information to send you notices and special offers via email. You may opt out of these emails at any time by clicking the "unsubscribe" link in these email notices/offers. 

We will not furnish personal information to an outside organization for its use in marketing or solicitation without your prior consent. 

We use personal information only for the purposes that we have disclosed to you. If for any reason your information is required to further a different purpose, we will notify you and ask you for your consent before we proceed. Only the information specifically requested is disclosed and we will take precautions to satisfy ourselves that the authorities who make the request have legitimate grounds to do so. We may disclose personal information as required by law and when we believe that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights and/or to comply with a judicial proceeding, court order, or legal process served on our website, if necessary, in certain limited circumstances such as a medical emergency, suspicion of illegal activity, or to collect on a delinquent account. We sometimes contract outside organizations to perform specialized services. Our trusted service suppliers may at times be responsible for processing and handling some of the information we receive from you. When you visit our website, information is not collected that could identify you personally unless you choose to provide it voluntarily. You are welcome to browse the website at any time anonymously and privately without revealing any personal information about yourself. 

If NorthWestPharmacy.com is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information. 

## Agents/Service Providers

We use other third parties such as affiliate dispensing pharmacies and fulfillment centers to fulfill orders, ACH check processing companies to bill you for goods and services, and an email service provider to send out emails on our behalf. When you create an account with us to purchase prescription and non-prescription products, we may share your name, address and medical profile information (i.e. height, weight, date of birth, gender, the existence and types of drug allergies, medications requested, medical history information, details of your existing medications, prescription information, and the name of your primary physician and their contact information). 

These third parties are prohibited from using your personally identifiable information for promotional purposes. 

NorthWestPharmacy.com does not share, sell, rent or trade your personal information with third parties other than as disclosed within this privacy policy. 

## Choice/Opt-Out 

If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or by emailing us at [CustomerService@NorthWestPharmacy.com](mailto:customerservice@northwestpharmacy.com). 

## Security Measures

We use current technologies and maintain security standards to ensure that your personal information is protected against unauthorized access, disclosure, inappropriate alteration or misuse. All safety and security measures are also appropriate to the sensitivity level of your information. Electronic client files are kept in a secure environment with restricted access. We manage our server environment appropriately and our firewall infrastructure is strictly adhered to. Our security practices are reviewed periodically and we employ current technologies to assist us in protecting the confidentiality and privacy of your information. In the course of daily operations, we attempt to restrict access to personal information to authorized employees who have a legitimate business purpose and reason for accessing it. As a condition of their employment, all employees of NorthWestPharmacy.com are required to abide by the privacy standards we have established and to follow all applicable laws and regulations. Unauthorized access to and/or disclosure of client information by an employee of NorthWestPharmacy.com is strictly prohibited. All employees are expected to maintain the confidentiality of personal information at all times and failing to do so will result in appropriate disciplinary measures, which may include dismissal. 

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information (such as personal health information) on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL). 

## Accessing and Amending Your Information

If your or your family members personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct or update it by making the change within the "My Account" section of the site or by emailing our Customer Support at [CustomerService@NorthWestPharmacy.com](mailto:customerservice@northwestpharmacy.com). We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services, contact us at [CustomerService@NorthWestPharmacy.com](mailto:customerservice@northwestpharmacy.com). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

Your family members may contact us at [CustomerService@NorthWestPharmacy.com](mailto:customerservice@northwestpharmacy.com) to request that we remove their information from our database. 

## Cookies

Technologies such as: cookies, beacons, tags and scripts are used by NorthWestPharmacy.com and our affiliates, analytics or service providers. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movements around the site, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis. 

We use cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited. 

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or clickstream data. 

We do not link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you. 

## Flash LSOs

Third parties, with whom we partner or provide certain features on our site or to display advertising based upon your Web browsing activity, use HTML5 to collect and store information. To learn how to manage privacy and storage settings for Flash cookies [click here](http://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/settings_manager.html#117118). 

## Behavioral Targeting

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

## Links to Other Sites

If you click on a link to a third party site, including on an advertisement, you will leave the NorthWestPharmacy.com site you are visiting and go to the site you selected. Because we cannot control the activities of third parties, we cannot accept responsibility for any use of your personally identifiable information by such third parties, and we cannot guarantee that they will adhere to the same privacy practices as NorthWestPharmacy.com. We encourage you to review the privacy statements of any other service provider from whom you request services. If you visit a third party website that is linked to NorthWestPharmacy.com, you should read that site’s privacy statement before providing any personally identifiable information. 

## Social Media Widgets

Our web site includes Social Media Features, such as Twitter button and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

## Meet Our Patients page/Testimonials

We display personal testimonials of satisfied customers on our site in addition to other endorsements. With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you wish to update or delete your testimonial, you can contact us at [CustomerService@NorthWestPharmacy.com](mailto:customerservice@northwestpharmacy.com). 

## Changes in this Privacy Statement

If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the home page, and other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. 

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page. 

PRIVACY OFFICER  
**NorthWestPharmacy.com**  
Valley Centre  
PO Box 56056  
Langley, BC, Canada  
V3A 8B3
